Joseph Luccisano

3 rue d'Occitanie 31290 Montgaillard-Lauragais Mobile. +33 6 73 68 74 61

E-mail: joseph.luccisano@gmail.com

Driving license (2003/10/26)

French nationality, born on 1985/02/23

Portfolio: <u>jluccisano.github.io</u> Online CV: <u>j.luccisano.free.fr</u> Web site: <u>www.nextrun.fr</u> Github: github.com/jluccisano

Linkedin: <u>jluccisano</u>



Full Stack Software Engineer

I'm a Full Stack Developer with 8 years of experience. I acquired some knowledge in different area which allow me to better understand things to go even further. I always want to learn more, that's why I created this blog in order to share my knowledge.

EXPERIENCES

Full Stack Developer

2014 - Now

EVS Broadcast Equipment, Toulouse France

In an Agile team, I contribute to design a distributed architecture whose purpose is to ingest and process media files through a BPMN Process Engine (transform, transfer, analysis...). In an Agile team, I contribute to design a distributed architecture whose purpose is to ingest and process media files through a BPMN Process Engine (transform, transfer, analysis...).

Java, Spring, RabbitMQ, AngularJs, HTML5, MongoDB, Docker, Git, Sass, CSS, Groovy, XSLT, PEG, Youtube API, Facebook Open Graph API, Twitter API, JsonSchema, JsonPath.

Lead Developer

2012 - 2014

NéoSoft Services, Toulouse France

Lead developer & SCRUM Master in a team of 7 developers.

Java, Spring, AngularJs, HTML5, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Git, Jenkins, Nexus.

IoT Software Engineer

2010 - 2012

Sierra Wireless, Toulouse France

Under the responsibility of a project manager. Designed B2C (Business To Customer) solutions to monitor remote communicating objects in the areas of advertising, automotive, energy and telecommunications.

Java, Spring, RabbitMQ, MySQL, JQuery, Hibernate, Svn, Ant+lvy.

Software Engineer

2009

Photobox, Paris France

Design and development of new components for company websites in the field of digital photo on the internet.

Java, Spring, Adobe Flex.

Software Engineer

2009

Intech, Luxembourg

Migration of risk management software, from a heavy client (Java / Swing) to a light client (Java / Flex).

Java, Spring, Adobe Flex, MySQL.

PROJECTS

Home automation

iluccisano.github.io

This is my portfolio where I put in place concrete architectures to both train me on new technologies but also to put in place things useful in my house (eg: Create a sprinkler system, Create a reactive weather station ...).

Java, Spring, RabbitMQ, InfluxDB, Docker, Raspberry PI, μService, IoT (Internet of Things), Git, REST, Swagger, Maven, ES6, D3js, Gulp, Python, ReactJS, WebSocket, Stomp, Jekyll.

NextRun

www.nextrun.fr

Passionate about sports, I developed a web site that allows to create and share routes, referencing events and planning sport workout.

AngularJs, Node.Js, MongoDB, Google Maps API, Highcharts, CSS,Sass, Jade, Bootstrap, Yeoman, Karma, Jasmine.

MAIN SKILLS

Dev: Java, Spring, RabbitMQ, MongoDB, Python, NodeJS;

DevOps: Docker, GIT, Maven, Grunt;

Web: AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS; **Architectures**: μService, REST, SOA;

OS: MacOS, Linux (Arch, Debian, Ubuntu, Raspbian);

Ongoing independent learning: Ansible, Kubernates, Mantl, Kivy, ReactJS.

EDUCATION

Graduated from University of Nancy Henri Poincaré

2009 - Master Degree's in System Networks Engineering 2007 - Bachelor in Electronic, Automation and Networks; 2006 - DUT in Electronic and Computer Science (GEII);

LANGUAGES

French: Maternal English: Professional

INTERESTS

Sports: Triathlon, Trail, Cycling, Swimming, Home automation.